A Guide to the Falls Church, Virginia Collection, 1934-1993
Virginia Room, Fairfax County Public Library
The Falls Church, Virginia Collection, 1934-1993
Fairfax County Public Library
MSS 03-08
.25 linear feet
The Falls Church, Virginia Collection consists of .25 linear feet and spans the years 1934-1993. The collection consists of various ephemera detailing the history of Falls Church, Virginia, including newspaper articles, informational brochures, event programs, a letter, a personal history, a speech, booklets, and a bumper sticker and pin.
Virginia Room staff
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None
Acquisition Information
Collection assembled by Virginia Room staff over a period of years. Items came from unknown donors; Francis Copeland of Phoenix, Arizona, donated the Chimney Villa memoranda booklet in August 2017.
Historical and Biographical Information
Falls Church is an independent city located in Northern Virginia just west of Washington, D.C. In 1734, an Episcopalian group founded The Falls Church, which facilitated population and economic growth in the area. Falls Church was the location of troupe encampments during the early years of the Civil War and witnessed several raids led by Mosby’s Rangers. Ten years after the war ended Falls Church became a township and in 1948 was granted status as an independent city.
Scope and Content
The Falls Church, Virginia Collection consists of .25 linear feet and spans the years 1934-1993. The collection consists of various ephemera detailing the history of Falls Church, Virginia, including newspaper articles, informational brochures, event programs, a letter, a personal history, a speech, booklets, and a bumper sticker and pin. Items focus on Falls Church history, primarily individual events and locations.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
None
None
Index Terms
Bailey’s Crossroads (Va.) - History; Falls Church (Va.) - History; Seven Corners (Va.) - History
Container List
- Newspaper, “The Penny Press” Arlington-Falls Church-Alexandria-Fairfax, 1951 April (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Program, Dedication of Kingsley Commons (Formerly Jefferson Village), 1984 July 27 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Brochure, “Citizens with a Mission: Historic Preservation”. Falls Church Historical Commission, 1979 August (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Brochures, “Historical Falls Church, Virginia” Falls Church Historical Development Commission, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Brochure, “Falls Church, Virginia”, Greater Falls Church Chamber of Commerce, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Brochure, “Trailing Through the History of Falls Church”, Mary Riley Styles Public Library, 1980 September (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Brochure, “Falls Church, The Evolution of a Virginia Village”, Falls Church Village Preservation and Improvement Society, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Brochure, “Historic Falls Church, Inc.”, Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- “Centennial Program, Falls Church, 1875-1975”, 1975 March 31 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- “Early History of the Methodist Church in Falls Church” by Benjamin R. Shreve, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- “Falls Church 22042: A Modern Postal Village” speech by Nan Netherton, 1993 April 23 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- “The Iron Worker” Vol. 14 No. 4, Fall Issue 1950. Lead Article of Falls Church, Virginia, 1950 Fall (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Program, Falls Church Festival, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Blank auto journal, Seven Corners Gulf service station (1101 E. Broad St), Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Letter, Homer Hoyt to Fairfax County Planning Commission, Re: Seven Corners Shopping Center, 1953 May (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Bailey’s Crossroads bumper stickers and pin, Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
- “The Sunday Star Pictorial Magazine” article about Falls Church pp. 7-8, 1949 March 6 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Falls Church Medical Center informational booklet, Undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Memoranda booklet, Chimney Villa, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 19)